At UCLA, social
psychologist Dr. Hal
Hirschfield put human
participants into fMRI
brain scanners to
investigate how the
brain visualizes time.
When researchers ask
people to think
about who they
are right now,
their current feelings,
their current hunger,
their current stress,
a specific region
called the medial
prefrontal cortex lit
up like a
Christmas tree.
Next, they ask
participants to think
about a total
stranger, a random
person waiting for
a bus in
another city.
As expected, that
self -processing neural
circuit powered
down completely.
Then came
the breakthrough.
Hirschfield asked
participants to think
about their future
self, the version
of them that
would exist in
10 years, next
month, or even
tomorrow morning.
Neurologically, something
jaw -dropping happened.
The brain processed